Karl Hubenthal Papers
Karl Hubenthal Papers
1952-1967
Hubenthal, Karl,1917-
3.5 linear ft.
Papers of the American editorial cartoonist including original editorial cartoons (1952-1966) as well as correspondence, writings and memorabilia
149063
Biographical History
Karl Hubenthal (1917-1998) was an American sports and editorial cartoonist.
Born in Beemer, Nebraska on May 1, 1917, Hubenthal grew up in Los Angeles, California and graduated from Hollywood High School. Hubenthal got his start in 1935 at the Los Angeles Herald-Express, where his first job was with the Art Department. In 1939 he began to do sports cartoons for that newspaper. Hubenthal left to serve with the Marine Corps during World War II and following the war worked as a freelance advertising artist.
But in 1949 he was drawn back into cartooning at another Hearst paper, the Examiner and in 1956 he became the paper's full-time editorial cartoonist. When the Herald Express was combined with the Examiner in 1962, Hubenthal's cartoons were one of the Examiner's features carried over to the newly combined publication. Hubenthal's cartoons were also syndicated to other Hearst newspapers and he continued to contribute sports cartoons to the paper on Fridays and drew other sports-themed commercial art pieces.
Hubenthal's work has been widely recognized. In 1940, he was named Best Sports Cartoonist at the New York World's Fair and the National Cartoonists Society gave him four awards for his sports cartoons. Through his sports cartoons, he supported the effort to bring the Dodgers baseball team to Los Angeles and Hubenthal routinely cariciatured local teams including the University of Southern California. The American Association of Editorial Cartoonists presented Hubenthal with the National Headliner's Award in 1958, 1960 and 1961. NCS also named him best editorial cartoonist in 1961, 1967 and 1970. Twenty-five Freedoms Foundation Medals were presented to him and he was nominated for the Pulitzer Prize several times. He served as president of the AAEC and the Society of Illustrators.
Karl Hubenthal retired in 1982 and died of cancer in Los Angeles on August 13, 1998.
"The nice part of what I do is that I get instant responses. I either get panned, or praised, but at least I know what I'm saying is having some effect. When you don't get mail, that's when you should worry." ( Herald-Examiner, 1982)
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Karl Hubenthal Papers are divided into four series.
Cartoons contains 428 original editorial cartoons drawn by Hubenthal for the Los Angeles Herald Examiner. Hubenthal depicted a mix of national and international issues as well as events specific to California and Los Angeles. At times, Hubenthal advocated in favor of certain issues including the prevention of traffic fatalities, increasing expenditures for schools, and supporting the annual Easter and Christmas seal campaigns. In one cartoon he attempted to involve readers in the issue of Alaska's statehood by drawing a star that the reader could clip out and mail to their senator asking them to make Alaska the 49th state.
In portraying political figures, Hubenthal often drew oversized objects for his caricatures to interact with. California Governor Pat Brown wears a gigantic cowboy hat of Lyndon B. Johnson’s while in another, a donkey is surrounded by towering elephant legs labeled with Republican Party candidates and Hubenthal illustrates desires to cut government spending with a small donkey and elephant trying to wield a bulky pair of scissors.
The cartoons were drawn on illustration board with ink, crayon and captions appear in pencil. Nearly all are dated but several are only marked with specific years.
Correspondence is arranged chronologically and consists largely of incoming letters. The letters primarily include fan mail and requests for original cartoons. Notable correspondents include: Ray C. Bliss (May 25, July 6, 1966), Herc Ficklen (Dec. 29, 1966, Jan. 11, 1967), Barry Goldwater (June 17, 1966), Reg Manning (June 3, June 27, 1966), Wayne Morse (March 4, 1966), George Murphy (July 16, 1965, May 21, 1966), and Richard Nixon (May 12, June 1, 1966), as well as members of President Johnson's staff requesting original cartoons for Johnson (July 23, Sept. 4, Nov. 8, 1965; Jan. 5, March 16 and 19, May 25, 1966- often the letters contain a photocopy of the cartoon that was sent to Johnson). A letter from William Randolph Hearst Jr. (May 24, 1966) discusses the work of cartoonist Richard Wallmeyer. There are also letters from Los Angeles Rams coach George Allen and fellow cartoonists Bert Whitman and John Fischetti.
Writings consists of two articles about editorial cartooning written by Hubenthal that appeared in The Quill and California Publisher.
Memorabilia contains one folder of biographical information, programs and clippings about Hubenthal's visit to the White House as well as a drawing of Lyndon B. Johnson done in ballpoint pen.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence and editorial cartoons are arranged chronologically.
Related Material
has collections of over one hundred cartoonists. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Cartoonists; Brown, Edmund G. (Edmund Gerald), 1905-1996 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Eisenhower, Dwight D. (Dwight David), 1890-1969 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Hubenthal, Karl, 1917-; Johnson, Lyndon B. (Lyndon Baines), 1908-1973 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Kennedy, John F. (John Fitzgerald), 1917-1963 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Khrushchev, Nikita Sergeevich, 1894-1971 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Hearst Newspaper Syndicate.; United States. Congress -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Los Angeles Herald examiner.; American wit and humor, Pictorial.; Caricatures and cartoons -- United States.; Cartoonists -- California.; Cartoonists -- United States.; Charity -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Editorial cartoons -- California -- Los Angeles.; Editorial cartoons -- United States.; Labor unions -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Taxation -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Traffic fatalities -- Caricatures and cartoons.; World politics -- 1945-1989 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Los Angeles (Calif.) -- Caricatures and cartoons.; United States -- Politics and government, 1945-1989 -- Caricatures and cartoons.; Articles.; Cartoons (humorous images); Correspondence.; Editorial cartoons.; Memorabilia.; Cartoonists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Karl Hubenthal, 1968.
Inventory
- Editorial cartoons, 428 items 14"x 17"
  - 1952 (Oversize 1, Folder 1)
    Feb. 3 What good is a watchdog if we don't feed it?: Los Angeles, civil defense
    Mar. 11 - These are sleepless nights!: Russia, NATO
    Mar. 23 - Clean sweep!: taxes, California
    Apr. 20 - Our happy perennials.: Los Angeles
    May 18 - It happens every spring!: vacation
    June 2 - Of primary importance!: voting, elections
    Aug. 30 - Dead end.: Labor Day, traffic fatalities
    Sept. 4 - Miss L.A. and Uncle Sam: Los Angeles, population
    Oct. 26 - Quick, while he's not looking...: bossism, California, elections
    Nov. 16 - Just what she wanted -- and needed: Los Angeles
    Dec. 14 - All us last minute shoppers: Christmas
    Dec. 30 - Holiday spirits: traffic fatalities
  - 1953 (Oversize 1, Folder 2)
    Jan. 25 - Grown out of his britches: California, highway construction
    Mar. 15 - The hides of March: taxes
    Mar. 16 - Rising curve: traffic fatalities
    Mar. 30 - Double barreled!: taxes, California
    May 29 - Speedway U.S.A.: Memorial Day, traffic
    Aug. 17 - Uninvited guest: China, United Nations
    Aug. 24 - The millstone: Los Angeles, traffic, industry
    Sept. 20 - Batter up!: cost of living, politics
    Sept. 27 - At least, it's in sight: taxes
  - 1954 (Oversize 1, Folder 3)
    Jan. 3 - Boy, am I glad to see you!: Congress, elections
    Jan. 26 - Flying saucer and cup': food prices
    Feb. 22 - Pointing the way: defense, war, peace
    Apr. 9 - In a new light: nuclear weapons, highway construction, civil defense
    May 12 - We will never learn: diplomacy, peace, communism
    June 12 - Elephant walk: Dwight Eisenhower, Congress
    June 21 - Siren song: vacation
    July 26 - H(ot) A(ir) Bomb!: Congress
    Aug. 3 - Blow but sure: Congress, Dwight Eisenhower, politics
    Sept. 3 - I'm stalking behind you: Labor Day, traffic fatalities
    Dec. 25 - Santa's shadow: Christmas
  - 1955 (Oversize 1, Folder 4)
    Jan. 5 - Now it's his turn...: Congress, Republican Party, Democratic Party
    Mar. 16 - Speaking of non-stop drummers...: Vyacheslav Molotov
    Apr. 3 - Can barely hear him: China, Nikolai Bulganin
    July 14 - Just when it was shaping up, too.: Dwight Eisenhower, Democratic Party, Dixon-Yates contract
    July 15 - Dispossessed!: armed Forces, Congress
    July 29 - Recommended summer reading: Congress, taxes, Hoover Commission
    Sept. 11 - Pardon us if we're skeptical: budget, taxes
    Oct. 2 - How about this, "torture course?": armed forces, roads
    Nov. 22 - Holiday reminder: Thanksgiving, safe driving
    Nov. 27 - Needs inspecting: taxes, Congress
    Dec. 19 - Yule-tide: Christmas
    Dec. 31 – I’ll pick you up right after the party...: traffic fatalities
  - 1956 (Oversize 1, Folder 5)
    June 14 - What so proudly we display: U.S. Flag
    June 17 - It's loaded' with good wishes: Father's Day
    Nov. 10 - Tidal wave: elections, democracy
    Nov. 23 - It's later than you think: Thanksgiving, Christmas
    Nov. 26 - Get in step to stamp out TB.: tuberculosis, charity, Christmas
    Dec. 3 - Do you fit the picture?: charity
    Dec. 26 - Disillusioned again.: taxes
    Dec. 28 - Written of the wind: California, wildfires
    1956 - Occasion of note: Hollywood Bowl
  - Jan-Aug 1957 (Oversize 1, Folder 6)
    Jan. 11 - The state of the nation: foreign policy, domestic affairs
    Jan 18- Curb rein: inflation
    Jan. 22 - The price tag: government spending
    Feb 18 - Altitude race: government spending, birth rate
    Mar. 5 - It's time to (Red) Cross this palm with silver: charity
    Mar 28 - For best supporting role: Academy Awards, United States
    Apr. 3 - Just follow the dotted lines: Congress, government spending
    Apr. 19 - Crown of thorns: communism
    Apr 21 - Message of the Ages: Christianity, Easter
    May 1- The Key: progress
    May 2 - Blunted edge: Congress, budget
    May 12 - We're still tied: Mother's Day
    May 23 - Recipe for havoc: weather
    Jun 16- King for a Day: Father's Day
    July 4 - Enough light to read by: Independence Day, Russia
    Aug. 28 - Practically in the bag: Congress, civil rights, foreign aid
  - Sep-Dec 1957 (Oversize 1, Folder 7)
    Sep 2 - Any question as to who's the healthiest?: labor, Soviet Union
    Sept. 27 - Misguided missile: inflation
    Oct. 1 - Out of this world: sports
    Oct. 5 - Early development: newspaper boys
    Oct. 17 - Sir Walter was a piker!: Queen Elizabeth II
    Oct. 26 - The catalyst: science, Britain
    Nov. 11 - Mere words cannot express...: veterans
    Nov. 14 - Doing his best to explode it: Middle East, Gamal Abdel Nasser
    Nov. 15 - Tight squeeze: automobiles
    Nov. 17 - Caught in the backwash: nuclear weapons, taxes
    Nov. 27 - Early bird: Thanksgiving, Christmas
    Nov. 29 - Progress report: stock market, Dwight Eisenhower
    Dec. 5 - May we suggest...: Hoover Commission, defense, science, cost of living
    Dec. 13 - Reflect a shining example: Christmas, charity
    Dec. 22- Bottoms up!: alcohol use, traffic fatalities, holidays
    Dec. 27 - Sounding board: disarmament, nuclear weapons, peace
    Dec. 30 - "I predict...": prosperity
  - Jan-Mar 1958 (Oversize 1, Folder 8)
    Jan. 1 - Enter...the space age.: space exploration
    Jan. 4 - One resolution we must keep.: nuclear weapons
    Jan. 20 - Reuther's 1958 model: Walter Reuther, United Auto Workers
    Jan. 24 - Transfusion may be necessary: Dwight Eisenhower, defense
    Jan. 29 - Greater horizons: college students
    Feb. 6 - Traffic cop needed: aeronautics
    Feb. 21 - That one was loaded.: weather
    Feb. 22 - First in war--first in space...: defense, space exploration
    Feb. 24 - Benson's biggest crop failure: Ezra Taft Benson, farming
    Feb. 27 - Trying to tune it in: television, FCC
    Mar. 1 - It's there,--just in case: taxes, Dwight Eisenhower
    Mar. 2 - Keeping it under the hat: Dwight Eisenhower, Richard Nixon
    Mar. 3 - It has to be a two-way street: trade, Europe
    Mar. 7 - We shot an arrow into the air...is it still wandering around out there?: space exploration
    Mar. 26 - Another cold war: FCC, government regulation
    Mar. 27 - For best supporting role: Gamal Abdel Nasser, Nikita Khrushchev
    Mar. 31 - Hash marks, '58 style
  - Apr-Jul 1958 (Oversize 2, Folder 1)
    Apr. 6 - Easter's message: Easter
    Apr. 9 - No help at all: California, water
    Apr. 17 - The back seat driver: Harry Truman, Dwight Eisenhower
    Apr. 28 - 0ur open door policy: economy
    May 1 - All around the maybe pole: taxes, Congress
    May 7 - Didn't have enough nerve to pull it himself: Congress, unions
    May 9 - Another mid-air collision avoided: airline industry, strikes
    May 11 - She's got the whole world in her hands.: Mother's Day
    May 14 - Can he get it through?: foreign aid, Dwight Eisenhower, Congress
    May 22 - Bird of prey: Armed forces, airline industry
    May 28 - Only a mirage: taxes
    June 2 - The key: schools, elections
    June 14 - You can add the 49th star: Congress, Alaska
    June 18 - What's brewing in the samovar?: Soviet Union, Nikita Khrushchev
    July 2 - Toughest obstacle on the course: Armed forces
    July 3 - It'll be a bang-up week-end: Independence Day, traffic fatalities
    July 30 - Patching up the ballet holes: John Foster Dulles, Iraq, foreign aid
    July 31 - Tough one to pin down: Nikita Khrushchev
  - Aug-Oct 1958 (Oversize 2, Folder 2)
    Aug. 3 - Wouldn't it be easier to trim the stack?: government spending
    Aug. 7 - Reversing his field: Nikita Khrushchev, Anglo-Americans
    Aug. 11 - Help: Help!: Hawaii, labor, Congress
    Aug. 13 - Which will it be?: United Nations, peace
    Aug. 14 - Building blocks vs. brick bats: United Nations, Dwight Eisenhower, Andrei Gromyko, Soviet Union
    Aug. 24 - Inundated!: judicial system, California
    Aug. 31 - Couldn't stand the shock': Los Angeles, taxes
    Sept. 1 - Dangerous flaw: labor
    Sept. 4 - Bird sanctuary: space exploration, peace, United Nations
    Sept. 6 - Outgrows 'em faster'n we can make: schools
    Sept. 8 - A little extra effort during the summer...means more contentment during the winter! Social Security: Social Security
    Sept. 10 - Cannon conference: Formosa
    Sept. 19 - We'll be hearing this from now 'til November: labor, Congress, Democratic Party, Republican Party
    Oct. 8 - Bringing up the heavy artillery: Dwight Eisenhower, Congress
    Oct. 19 - The Jet age: population, birth rate
    Oct. 22 - Just when it was cooling off: Quemoy
    Oct. 30 - We must make it!: charity
    Oct. 31 - The gobble-ins: taxes, California, elections
  - Nov-Dec 1958 (Oversize 2, Folder 3)
    Nov. 3 - "Get lost.": elections, California, bigotry
    Nov. 11 - There are no words...: Veterans
    Nov. 12 - Which comes first--chicken or egg?: nuclear weapons, Soviet Union
    Nov. 16 - Which kind of genii--slave or master?: labor, Democratic Party, elections
    Nov. 17 - After seeing the new ones: automobile industry
    Nov. 20 - Anybody even looking for the key?: foreign policy
    Nov. 26 - Not a crumb left for stuffing: California, budget
    Dec. 1 - Help fence it in: muscular dystrophy, charity
    Dec. 7 - "...What was that?": defense, Soviet Union
    Dec. 15 - "...Let nothing you dismay": NATO, Berlin
    Dec. 23 - He'll be happy to fill it: Congress, taxes
    Dec. 25 - "Yet, in the Bark street shineth an everlasting light...!": peace
  - Jan-Apr 1959 (Oversize 2, Folder 4)
    Jan. 1 - "C'mon in.": space exploration
    Jan. 4 - Next?: New Year's
    Jan. 12 - The importance of printing: journalism, International Printing Week
    Jan. 25 - The little man who isn't there: taxes, Democratic Party, Republican Party
    Feb. 6 - It' s tough to keep 'em in line: Europe, John Foster Dulles
    Feb. 9 - Saps: crime
    Feb. 14 - With luv to the Gov.: California, Pat Brown, budget
    Feb. 18 - Maybe this one will iron it out: Germany
    Feb. 25 - Let's stay on the beam: economy, Dwight Eisenhower
    Mar. 6 - Unpredictable weather: Nikita Khrushchev
    Mar. 12 - Up--down--up--down: peace
    Mar. 16 - How to complete the picture: Easter Seals, charity
    Mar. 19 - Next stop, Geneva?: Harold Macmillan
    Apr. 1 - April Pool?: Soviet Union, peace
    Apr. 26 - Lumpy mattress: economy, unemployment
    Apr. 30 - Putting his best pussyfoot forward: elections, John F. Kennedy, labor, Congress
  - May-Dec 1959 (Oversize 2, Folder 5)
    May 6 - Bumper forecast: farming, Ezra Taft Benson
    June 4 - Study in still life: foreign policy
    June 18 - There are sharks in the air, too': Soviet Union, military
    July 24 - His blind spot: Congress, Dwight Eisenhower
    Aug. 10 - Yes or no, let 'em know: Dwight Eisenhower, Congress, labor
    Aug. 14 - No records this month: steel industry, strikes
    Oct. 7 - America's position of strength: prayer
    Nov. 22 - Start 'em Humming: Christmas, charity
    Nov. 23 - Easing up: federal reserve
    Nov. 29 - The new economy model, we presume?: budget, Dwight Eisenhower
    Dec. 10 - Fooling no one: elections
  - Jan-May 1960 (Oversize 2, Folder 6)
    Jan. 4 - Just like our resolutions: Congress, elections
    Jan. 20 - Right between the I's: Dwight Eisenhower, budget, taxes, Congress, elections
    Jan. 29 - A bigger "A'; test: Charles de Gaulle, Algeria, France, nuclear weapons
    Jan. 31 - Right in style: fashion
    Feb. 8 - That was no draft!: Lyndon B. Johnson, California
    Feb. 14 - "She's my valentine!": Democratic Party, California, John F. Kennedy, Hubert Humphrey, Stuart Symington, Pat Brown
    Mar. 24 - Can-opener: motion pictures, communism
    Mar. 28 - The support they need: Easter Seals, charity
    Apr. 4 - Oscar for Sinatra: Albert Maltz, communism
    Apr. 18 - No more reprieves: taxes
    Apr. 27 - Strategic Retreat: Korea, Syngman Rhee
    May 10 - Pause for reflection': California, water, Supreme Court
    May 22 - To the Hilt!: Dwight Eisenhower, Nikita Khrushchev
  - Jun-Dec 1960 (Oversize 2, Folder 7)
    June 6 - Try these for size: elections, women
    June 9 - Couldn't wait for a draft: Nelson Rockefeller, Richard Nixon,
    July 3 - What about reentry problems?: Congress, politics
    Aug. 4 - Just a hard to swallow: Cuba, Fidel Castro
    Aug. 31 - Countdown: Congress, elections
    Sept. 18 - Safety guard: United Nations, communism
    Sept. 25 - National plowing contest: Richard Nixon, John F. Kennedy, farm vote, Ezra Benson Taft
    Oct. 19 - Wet matches: John F. Kennedy, Richard Nixon
    Oct. 30 - "I'm more scared by that one, sonny.": water, California
    Nov. 23 - Cigar snuffer: Latin America, Fidel Castro
    Nov. 30 - Hands across the sea: foreign aid, Europe
    Dec. 3 - Basin Street Blues: segregation, judicial system
    Dec. 28 - Delayed Christmas: Democratic Party
  - Jan-Jul 1960 (Oversize 3, Folder 1)
    Jan. 3 - Expanded--'61: economy, California
    Jan. 15 - It's swarming season: Los Angeles, elections
    Feb. 8 - Double dilemma: weather, California
    Feb. 24 - Cat an a hot tin roof: airline industry, strikes
    Feb. 27 - Slow eater: John F. Kennedy, Congress
    Mar. 5 - Reverse trend: economy
    Mar. 23 - No apple for the teacher: Congress, schools
    Mar. 30 - K.O.' d: defense, John F. Kennedy
    May 1 - Green corpuscles: investment
    May 7 - Fast shuffle: Los Angeles, Sam Yorty, elections
    May 30 - Sorrow upon sorrow: traffic fatalities
    May 31 - By a thread: elections, Los Angeles
    June 25 - The hub: Los Angeles, aeronautics
    July 7 - Handicap race: sports, Russia
    July 23 - Plenty to count: Pat Brown, California, elections
    July 28 - We don't bluff Nikita: Walter Ulbricht, Nikita Khrushchev, John F. Kennedy
    July 31 - In language he understands: Berlin, Nikita Khrushchev
  - Aug-Dec 1961 (Oversize 3, Folder 2)
    Aug. 4 - "Cut!": John F. Kennedy, Congress
    Sept. 15 - Bumper crop: Los Angeles, county fair
    Sept. 28 - Spelling it out: John F. Kennedy, peace
    Oct. 1 - Fallout: taxes, Congress
    Oct. 11 - Nasty neighbor: nuclear weapons, Mao Zedong, Nikita Khrushchev
    Nov. 11 - Constant escort: peace, veterans
    Nov. 16 - It's the fall down that's dangerous: communism
    Nov. 19 - Deeper and deeper: Congo, United Nations
    Nov. 23 - With an extra-big wishbone: prosperity, peace, Thanksgiving
    Nov. 24 - Cold turkey: Konrad Adenauer, Berlin
    Dec. 17 - "Now you're getting it!": Latin America, John F. Kennedy
    Dec. 18 - Light Source: Christmas, charity
    Dec. 22 - Dimmer: holidays, traffic fatalities
    Dec. 26 - Oh! Oh!: Christmas
  - Jan-May 1962 (Oversize 3, Folder 3)
    Jan. 1 - Will it have the answers?: politics
    Jan. 23 - The iceman cometh: weather, California
    Jan. 24 - The right direction: YMCA, children
    Feb. 4 - Lowest of the low: violence
    Feb. 11 - The big winners: California, water, weather
    Feb. 12 - Lincoln Highway: democracy, Abraham Lincoln
    Feb. 18 - The only way to attain it: brotherhood
    Mar. 23 - Never trust a hitchhiker: John F. Kennedy, Nikita Khrushchev, space exploration
    Apr. 5 - Gulliver is beginning to stir: California, farmers, urban voters
    Apr. 13- Spring Steel: inflation, steel industry
    May 21 - Lesson in logic: elections, schools, California, Los Angeles
  - Jun-Dec 1962 (Oversize 3, Folder 4)
    June 20 - Ah-h-h, that's more like it!: Republican Party, California, Joe Shell
    July 9 - 3-stage rocket: vacation
    Oct. 10 - Tonic to stimulate the Grass roots: Dwight Eisenhower, John F. Kennedy
    Oct. 18 - Lock it up forever: polio
    Nov. 30 - Not so's you'd notice it: cost of living
    Dec. 6 - Give them a lift: Christmas, charity
    Dec. 20 - Disillusioning: taxes, government spending, John F. Kennedy
    Dec. 21 - Modern Mona Lisa: Christmas
  - Jan-Jul 1963 (Oversize 3, Folder 5)
    Jan. 10 - With the greatest of ease: John F. Kennedy, Congress
    Jan. 17 - "Bet we're in it again": budget,
    Jan. 31- Reminder: polio, Los Angeles
    Mar. 4 - Kick the can: Los Angeles, Sam Yorty, trash
    Apr. 1 - Don't be an April fool: voting
    Apr. 5 - Needs more trimming than that: John F. Kennedy, foreign aid, Congress
    Apr. 7 - Fills the ball: U.S. Dollar
    Apr. 15 - Easter nest egg roll: taxes
    May 20 - What about our short range target?: space exploration, Cuba
    May 23 - That's the point: Orville Freeman, farming, government regulation
    May 27 - Another "space" race: schools, election
    May 30 - Recessional: Memorial Day
    June 5 - Diversion channel: water, Supreme Court, California
    July 17 - Sunlight at last: nuclear weapons
    July 25 - Dunce cap: Los Angeles, trash
  - Aug-Dec 1963 (Oversize 3, Folder 6)
    Aug. 9 - "Not so fast, there": common market, tariffs
    Sept. 19 - Mast get together first: Congress, Republican Party, Democratic Party, taxes, John F. Kennedy, government spending
    Sept. 30 - "How does out grass roots garden grow?": conservation, John F. Kennedy
    Oct. 6 - Stamping ground: Honduras, Dominican Republic, Peru, Argentina
    Nov. 7 - Which way is the wind blowing?: Democratic Party, Republican Party, elections
    Nov. 8 - The cat is out of the cellophane bag: Nelson Rockefeller